sheplers.com 2019-07-19

# Privacy & Security

## SHEPLERS PRIVACY & SECURITY POLICY

This policy was last revised on: December 28, 2011. 

#### We're a Business You Can Trust

At Sheplers, above all else, we value our customers and understand your concerns about online privacy and security. Because we know that your privacy is very important, we have instituted policies intended to ensure that your personal information is always respected and handled in a safe and responsible manner. This Privacy Statement is designed to help you understand what information we collect, how we use it, the steps we take to safeguard it and the choices you have regarding the use of and your ability to review and correct the information. 

When you visit our web site, we automatically recognize your Internet service provider, the Web page from which you came, and a record of your activity on our site, but you cannot be identified as an individual. The customer information that Sheplers Store collects through its web site is used to process orders and to improve your shopping experience. 

We use the information you share with us to improve your shopping experience by allowing us to make our Web site easier and more enjoyable to use. The information you volunteer enables us to process our purchases, confirm your orders, customize the content and layout of our pages, notify you about updates to our site, and provide you with additional information about our products. We do not sell or share any of your personal information with third-parties or use the information you provide in any way other than as identified above. 

The information you supply to us is added to our customer database. We may also send you catalogs or emails to inform you of new products, services and special offers, special promotions or upcoming events. You can remove yourself from our email list at any time. 

When you provide personal information at our stores, our call centers, our websites or through our authorized third parties, you are consenting to our policies, as described herein, on how Sheplers will collect, use, disclose and manage your personal information. 

#### Privacy & Security Policy Quick Reference

Click on any link below to find more information about that privacy or security policy. 

  * What information do we collect?
  * How do we use your information?
  * How can you control the use of your information?
  * How do you we safeguard your information?
  * What technologies do you use to enhance my shopping experience?
  * Children's Privacy
  * Changes to this Privacy Statement
  * How to Contact Us
  * Conflict in Terms

#### What information do we collect?

We use various methods of gathering information to help ensure that your shopping experience is as efficient and accommodating as possible. We collect information that you provide to us when you: 

  * Request a catalog or information about our products and services;
  * Purchase, return, or exchange a product;
  * Visit our website, retail store, or outlet location;
  * Create an online shopping account;
  * Contact our call center or customer service desk;
  * Provide us with comments or suggestions.

The type of information we may collect include the following: 

  * Anonymous site traffic information (in order to improve your shopping experience at our site);
  * Contact information such as name, mailing address, phone number, and email address; or
  * Personal information such as billing address and credit card information, when provided.

To better serve you and enhance your shopping experience, we may also supplement the information listed above with information from our joint marketing partners or third parties. 

Top of page

#### How do we use your information?

Sheplers wants to provide you with the most efficient and trustworthy shopping experience. We may use personal information that you provide to us in the following manner: 

  * To assist you in customer service communications;
  * To administer your account information, online forms, and other site features;
  * To enable you to check out and complete your purchase;
  * To send you special announcements or promotional information about new products or services and upcoming events;
  * To send you printed catalogs in the mail;
  * As necessary, to share your information with trusted third-party companies that provide support services; or
  * To aggregate non-personal information in order to help improve our website and system administration.

#### In-store Shopping.

When you visit one of our stores or outlet locations, you can shop anonymously when you pay with cash. However, we may keep a history of your purchases if you use a credit card or debit card. We collect this information in order to process your orders to better assist you, and all such information will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Statement. If you want to return or exchange purchased merchandise, we may ask you for personal identifying information such as the credit card used for the purchase or a picture ID to help prevent fraud. 

#### Customer Service.

If you provide us with your phone number, you may receive telephone contact from us for customer service communications, such as to ask you about your order. If you call our customer service toll-free number, we may ask you personal identifying information, depending on the nature of your request, to better assist you with your requests and questions. We may retain this information to help meet your future needs. 

#### Catalogs.

We may use your name and postal address to occasionally send you printed catalogs from Sheplers. We may also share such information, as described herein, to other reputable direct marketing companies who may have offers of interest to you. 

#### E-mails.

We may use your e-mail address to notify you about the status of your order, provide customer service information, answer your questions and requests, or occasionally send you sales notifications or other promotional information about our products and services. We will not sell or rent your e-mail address to outside marketing companies. 

#### Contests, Promotions or Surveys.

If you opt-in or participate in a contest, promotion, sweepstakes offering or survey (whether via on-line, over the phone or at one of our retail stores), we may use your personal information to manage your entry in such promotion, to notify you if you are a winner, or to fulfill promotional obligations. At the time of your entry or registration for a specific promotion, survey, contest, or sweepstakes, we will provide you with the rules governing such promotion, contest or survey. 

#### Authorized Third Parties.

To provide you with an optimal shopping experience, we partner with certain third parties to manage our customer information, to fulfill promotions, or to communicate with our customers. In such cases, we may disclose your personal information to such outside companies. We do not authorize any of these service providers to make any use of your information other than for our benefit. 

To provide you with other marketing information or third party promotions that may be of interest to you, we may disclose your name and postal address to reputable third parties, but not your e-mail address or other information. 

Such third parties may have websites with separate privacy and data collection practices, and we recommend that you carefully review them. If you would like to change how information is used on that third party website, you must do so directly with that third party. 

#### By Law.

In certain instances, we may disclose your personally identifiable information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action to protect your rights, the rights of Sheplers, or others. We may also disclose your personally identifiable information when we believe it is required by law. 

#### Sale of Business.

In the unlikely event that Sheplers is sold, or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information may be one of the transferred assets, and may therefore be used by a third party acquirer in accordance. 

#### Customers.

Under certain circumstances, we reserve the right to refuse to provide goods and services to customers or potential customers without explanation. 

Top of page

#### How can you control the use of your information?

We want you to be in control of your information, and we want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. 

#### E-mails and Newsletter.

If you do not want to receive our promotional emails, you may unsubscribe at any time by:

  * Visiting our contact us page and request to be unsubscribed; or
  * Clicking the remove link at the bottom of any promotional Sheplers e-mail;

#### Catalogs.

If you do not wish to receive our printed catalog, please contact us. When you give us your name and address as it appears on the mailing label, we will remove your contact information from our mailing list. Please allow several weeks for the catalogs to stop, as we schedule catalog delivery well in advance. If you receive a catalog from a third party, please contact that company directly to make any changes. We cannot alter or remove your information from any third parties' mailing lists. 

Top of page

#### How do you we safeguard your information?

Protecting the safety of your personal information, such as your credit card information, is important to us. Our online store includes a variety of technical, administrative and physical safeguards so that you can enjoy your shopping experience without having to worry about loss, misuse, or unauthorized access to your information. For example, we have the following security measures on our websites: 

#### Secure Shopping.

We use industry-standard encryption technologies to encrypt credit card and billing information while it is being transmitted to Sheplers. In addition, we use commercially reasonable efforts to stay up to date with best practices regarding the protection of information in connection with transactions occurring over the internet. We also use VeriSign as our SSL provider as an added measure for your protection. You may want to check your internet settings to make sure your browser is in compliance with industry-standard encryption technology. 

#### Firewalls.

After your order is received, we protect all of your private information, including your order, behind a network security system called a "firewall." Only select staff has access to this information, and then only to information necessary to service your order. 

#### Phone Orders.

Some versions of popular web browsers and some firewalls don't permit communication through secure servers like the ones we use to process orders. If your web browser cannot support this level of security, you will not be able to order products through out websites. If so, please phone us toll-free at 1-888-835-4004. 

We strive to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, but no data transmission over Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us over the Internet. Also, please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting credit card numbers. 

Top of page

#### What technologies do you use to enhance my shopping experience?

To improve our websites and to make your online shopping experience more enjoyable, we collect anonymous information of all visitors to our websites through the use of cookies, graphic tags, transactions and other technologies. 

#### Cookies.

Cookies are used for the express purpose of making your visits more worthwhile, and do not contain any personally identifying information (such as name or credit card information). Most browsers are preset to accept cookies and are used to make online shopping easier and faster for you. If you set your browser to refuse cookies, purchasing is not possible at the Sheplers site. In such cases, to place orders, you may call us at 1-888-835-4004. 

Sheplers also uses persistent cookies to identify members after their first visit. These cookies remain on the hard drive of a PC and allow a user to enter our site without having to log in on every visit. To access any secure areas such as your account information or checkout, you must still enter your password. 

#### Image Tags.

Our websites may also use analytics technology to optimize and tailor our websites for our visitors. This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on our websites. 

#### Third Party Links.

Our websites may include links to other websites which might take you away from our site, such as sites of outside business partners, vendors and advertisers. These sites have separate privacy and data collection practices. Sheplers has no control over such websites and is not responsible or liable for the privacy practices or information-gathering practices of other entities or web sites. Except as stated in this Privacy Statement, we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your prior consent. 

Top of page

#### Children's Privacy

This site is not directed towards children, and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under 13 years of age. 

#### Changes to the Privacy Statement

By using our website, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as described herein. Sheplers reserves the right to change, modify or amend this policy from time to time. We may send those customers who have not opted-out of our communications an email about any changes to our Privacy Statement. We encourage you to periodically review our current privacy policies. 

#### How to Contact Us

Our customers come first. If you have any concerns or questions, you can contact us by:

  * clicking on this link Contact Us;
  * writing to us at Sheplers, 6501 West Kellogg, Wichita, KS 67209;
  * Visit our website, retail store, or outlet location;
  * calling us toll-free at 1-888-835-4004; or
  * e-mailing us at service@sheplers.com.

#### Conflict in Terms

It is our goal to make our privacy practices easy to understand. We have created this easy-to-read Privacy Statement with that goal in mind. Some browsers utilize privacy enhancing technology to translate our Privacy Statement into a computer readable format. The technology then requires that the computer format be translated back into human readable format for you to read. This translation back into human readable format is often referred to as a "Policy Summary". It is possible that through these translations, the Policy Summary may unintentionally end up being inconsistent with the Privacy Statement upon which it is based. It might fail to address an issue or it might address an issue not raised in our Privacy Statement. For this reason, you should rely on our Privacy Statement as the most accurate and definitive description of our practices. 

Top of page
